When we think of solutions to global warming,
当考虑怎样去解决全球变暖时，
we generally think in terms of technology or policy,
我们通常会从技术或政策的角度思考，
but other approaches are necessary
但其他方面也很必要，
which have to do with how our societies are structured.
而这些方面与我们社会的构建相关。
The most important of them
其中最重要的，
is educating and empowering women and girls.
是去教育并赋权予妇女和女孩。
Now, don't take my word for it.
此刻，别把我的话当作耳旁风。
Its potential impact has been calculated by scientists.
科学家闷已衡量过其潜在影响。
Like, for instance, those working on Project Drawdown,
例如，那些致力于 Project Drawdown 项目的人们，
who focus on greenhouse gas emissions.
此项目关注温室气体排放。
They calculated that educating and empowering women and girls
他们得出教育并赋予妇女和女孩权力
is one of the single most important things
是我们应对碳污染
that we can do to confront carbon pollution.
可以做的最重要的事情之一。
It may result in a total reduction of CO2-equivalent gases
这可以帮助二氧化碳当量气体
of over 80 billion tons,
整体减少超过 800 亿吨，
which is not far from double the total annual global emissions.
这几乎是每年全球排放总量的两倍。
As a marine scientist and nature adventurer,
我是海洋科学家和自然探险家，
I've witnessed firsthand
我曾亲眼目睹
how climate change impacts the world we live in.
气候变化对我们 赖以生存的世界造成的影响。
These climate catastrophes have almost taken my life.
这些气候灾难曾险些让我丧命。
Like when I was nearly buried alive during an avalanche
比如，雪崩差点将我活埋，
or swept away by a cyclone.
还有龙卷风把我卷走。
Thankfully, I survived,
庆幸的是，我死里逃生，
but will our grandchildren call this planet home in 2050 or 2100
但若是情况继续恶化， 到 2050 或 2100 年时，
if our trajectory continues?
我们的子孙们 还会把这当作家园吗？
Coming from a male-dominated society,
我来自一个由男性主导的社会，
I've been asked all sorts of intrusive questions
各种各样的问题侵扰着我，
as to why I do what I do.
像是问道我为什么要做这些事。
"Can you even travel alone?"
“你一个人也能旅行吗？”
"Are you capable of climbing mountains with your heavier figure?
“你这么胖也能爬山吗？”
I mean, are you fit enough?"
“我的意思是， 你身材看起来爬不了？”
"Do you think, as a woman, you're equipped to do this?"
“你认为，女性有能力去做这吗？”
And the answer has always been, yes.
而答案一直是肯定。
I want to show my fellow Arab women that anything is possible,
我想告诉我的阿拉伯女性同胞们 一切皆有可能，
that being a woman should not be the end to your dreams,
作为一名女性 不应该是你梦想的终结，
that you are so much more than what you are conditioned to be,
你可以超越你所能，
and that you are indeed the solution to the crisis facing our planet.
并且你确实可以参与解决 我们地球的危机。
In 2020, women made up about 40 percent of the global workforce.
2020 年，女性约占全球劳动力的 40% 。
Women's shares in the Middle East are just under 25 percent.
中东女性的份额略低于 25%。
And these figures are way lower in the Gulf countries.
而这些指数在海湾地区国家还要低得多。
And considering that women make up nearly half of the Gulf,
考虑到女性占了海湾地区的近一半，
imagine how women's equal involvement in the economy
想象一下，女性平等参与经济
could enhance the overall growth of the region.
可以怎样促进该地区的整体增长。
Many labor laws state
众多劳动法宣称
that there's no discrimination between men and women.
男女平等。
Yet women's upward mobility is quite restricted
然而，女性的晋升空间备受限制，
and many senior positions are still being held by men.
而许多高级职位仍由男性主导。
The cultural perception that women are more emotional
认为女性更感性或更适合
or better suited to household responsibilities
承担家庭责任的文化观念
remains a serious obstacle for ambitious women
给有抱负的女性们带来了障碍
who end up underemployed.
以至于她们大多数 没法走上工作岗位。
So what does that have to do with the climate?
那么这与气候有什么关系呢？
Well, access to education, employment and family planning
接受教育、就业和计划生育
is the condition for more vibrant lives for women and girls,
会让妇女和女孩们、她们的家庭，
for their families and their entire communities.
乃至和整个社区更具活力。
They get to earn more money,
她们可以赚到更多的钱，
achieve career goals and face fewer health issues.
实现职业目标， 需要面对更少的健康问题。
And not only that, they become more resilient
不仅如此，她们会更有应变力，
and better equipped to manage both food and nature
更有能力处理膳食以及自然，
and to cope with the impacts of climate change.
并应对气候变化的影响。
Women are also the ones most at risk
当面临气候灾难的影响时，如飓风，
when it comes to impacts of climate catastrophes like cyclones,
女性时最容易受害的群体，
which have grown more frequent in my own home country of Oman.
在我的祖国阿曼， 飓风越来越频繁。
And why?
那么为什么呢？
Well because they're left with a charge of the children or elderly,
因为女性往往 留在家中照顾孩子或老人，
they don't know how to swim,
她们不会游泳，
or simply because they never had basic resilience skills taught to them,
或仅仅是因为从没有人教过她们 基本的应变技巧，
like building a shelter, making a fire
比如搭建避难所、生火，
or even administering basic first aid.
甚至是进行基本的急救。
In fact, UN figures indicate
事实上，联合国的数字表明
that 80 percent of people displaced by climate change
80% 因气候变化而流离失所的人
are women.
是女性。
And with more of these occurrences happening,
而随着更多这样情况的发生，
my gender will face more of the brunt
我的性别将面临更多冲击
further preventing them from achieving their potential
进一步阻止她们实现自己的潜力
and protecting themselves.
和保护她们自己。
This is why I founded WomeX,
这就是为什么我创立了 WomeX，
a platform where we teach women from my community negotiation skills
一个向我所在社区的女性 传授商谈技巧的平台，
to nurture a new wave of girl bosses in the region.
以培养当地新一批的女性领导者。
WomeX is on a mission to laying the groundwork
WomeX 致力于通过将当地情况
to combating climate change
与领导力培训相结合，
by bridging localized context and leadership training.
为应对气候变化打下基础。
By educating more women on these skills,
通过对更多女性进行技能教育，
we hope to equip them with the tools
我们希望给予她们
that allow them to control their careers and their lives,
掌握自己的职业与生活的工具，
and to contribute significantly to the collective efforts
并为应对碳污染所需的集体努力
necessary to confront carbon pollution.
做出重大贡献。
So far, we've supported a thousand
目前，我们已经支持了上千名女性，
and are working hard to achieve our ambitious goal of a million.
并正在努力实现 帮助上百万女性的远大目标。
Now, even though it has been
现在，尽管性别平等几年来
on the global sustainability radar for years,
一直在全球可持续发展的雷达上，
gender parity as a climate solution
但性别平等 作为一种气候解决方案
has not received the attention it deserves.
还没有得到应有的关注。
Now is the time to make it a priority.
是时候将视其为当务之急了，
Now is the time to educate and empower all women and all girls.
是时候教育并赋权予所有女性了。
Thank you.
谢谢大家。